Joseph Maluki Kitheka

Front-End React Developer

flutterhub1.21.0@gmail.com • +254795164401

https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-kitheka-4827a01a7/ • https://github.com/fhub-1 • https://www.youtube.com/chan-nel/UCAOdLWYUTCgX5PjNSI2DNIg
https://twitter.com/@josehub121

Summary

Hello. My name's Joseph maluki Kitheka and I'm 24 years old. I was always curious about software development and technology, so I went to Coursera with a double major in front-end development and computer science.

Skills

React • Redux • HTML5 • CSS3 • JavaScript • Node.js • Flutter • React native

Work Experience

Front-end React Developer

Jul 2021 – present

PwaniTeknowgalz • Part-time

mombasa, Kenya

Technologies: JavaScript • React • Node.js

at pwaniteknowgalz I am responsible on helping girls on building website's using ReactJS and tailwindcss

Front-end Developer

Nov 2017 - Jun 2021 • 3 yrs 7 mos

TECHKIDZ AFRICA • Contract

Mombasa, Kenya

Technologies: JavaScript • Flutter/dart • HTML/CSS • React Native • React

We are a Technology Academy that natures curiosity in Children of ages 7 to 19 by training them on Robotics, Animation, Gaming, Coding, App & Web development, Creative design thinking and 3D Printing.

Projects

KITECH SOLUTION

Jul 2022 – present

3 coworkers

Technologies: JavaScript • React • Next.js • MongoDB

KITECH SOLUTION is a full stack software development company based in Kenya. We are focused on delivering quality solutions for our clients' needs.

Educations

Certificate: Introduction to Front-End Development

Jul 2022 - Feb 2023 • 7 mos

Coursera | Meta

Mombasa, Kenya

Grade/GPA: 86.95%

Welcome to Introduction to Front-End Development, the first course in the Meta Front-End Developer program.

This course is a good place to start if you want to become a web developer. You will learn about the day-to-day responsibilities of a web developer and get a general understanding of the core and underlying technologies that power the internet. You will learn how front-end developers create websites and applications that work well and are easy to maintain.

Certificate: Software Development

Sep 2021 - Jul 2022 • 10 mos

Pluralsight

Mombasa, Kenya

Grade/GPA: 89%

Building efficient web and mobile interfaces is often challenging and requires the use of imperative logic. React enables you to declaratively describe user interfaces in terms of their state, and it will do the heavy lifting of natively building them for you. In this course, React: Getting Started, you will delve into the fundamental concepts about React and use them to build practical web applications. First, you will see how to design class components and stateful function component, how to one-way flow data and behavior in a component tree, and how to read and update state elements. Then, you will delve into modern JavaScript features used with React like arrow functions, destructuring rest and spread operators, classes, async/await, and more. Next, you will learn some core React tasks like taking input from the user, reading data from an API, managing side effects like timers, and sharing stateful logic with custom hooks. Finally, you will explore how to configure and use a local JavaScript development environment on your machine. When you are finished with this course, you will have the skills and knowledge you need to understand React projects, and start simple React applications from scratch.

Certification: Software Development

Sep 2021 – Jul 2022 • 10 mos

Pluralsight

Mombasa, Kenya

Grade/GPA: 78%

Node.js is a simple and powerful tool for backend JavaScript development. In this course, Building Web Applications with Node.js and Express 4.0, you will learn everything you need to know to get started in web development with Node.js. First, you will cover the basics of Node.js and how to select an IDE. Second, you will explore template engines and how to render in HTML out of Express. Next, you will learn all aspects of routing, including express middleware. Finally, you will work with multiple databases and backend APIs and will cover local security with Passport.js. By the end of this course, you will have all of the tools you need to build a full-stack web application with Node.js and Express.

Certifications & Awards

MONGODB FUNDAMENTALS - START WORKING WIT H NODE.JS + MONGODB - CODEDAMN	Apr 2021
REACT T UT ORIALS - CODEDAMN	Oct 2020
Introduction to Front-End Development - Meta	Jul 2022
JavaScript Arrays and Collections - Pluralsight	Dec 2021
React 17: Getting Started - Pluralsight	Nov 2021
Building Web Applications with Node.js and Express - Pluralsight	Oct 2021

Languages

English (Full professional proficiency)

Swahili (Elementary proficiency)